VINIT KUMAR

twitter.com/vinitkme vinit.kumar@changer.nl +91-8554862210

Summary

An experienced Web Developer with a good knowledge of Python and JavaScript based web development. I love creating products that are good in user experience and user interface. I love doing frontend and backend work alike and building end to end solutions for fun. I do bit of writing as well on my blogs here: http://www.gotchacode.com and http://vinitkumar.me

Contributing to Open Source is one of my passion and most of time you would find me closing issues on Github or reading some good piece of Code.

- Qualities:
 - Fast and Avid learner.
 - Consistent hard worker.
 - Never backing down from a challenge.
 - Punctual.

EDUCATION

B.E Civil Engineering

Sep 2012

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

CAREER HISTORY

Software Engineer, Changer, Pune

Feb 2013 - Present

- Currently I am helping build a Safe and Secure Social Network for Schools (http://www.socialschools.nl/en/). I also have experience working on our line of service offerings.
- My Core areas of interests and experience here are : Python/Django, JavaScript, Node Js and CSS with a bit of devops.

Freelance Web Developer, gadgetizor.com and digitizor.com

Summer 2011 - Jan 2013

• Worked on the design and scaling of wordpress based high traffic sites mentioned above.

Chrome Extension Developer, Worked on a E-Commerce based Chrome Extension and a official extension of Coderwall.com coderwall.com/api Sep 2012-Nov 2012

- Developed a full stack e-commerce based chrome Extension.
- Developed the Official Chrome Extension for Coderwall.com.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, AngularJS, CoffeeScript, Jquery, LATEX, BackBoneJS, PostgreSQL

Operating Systems: OS X, Linux, Windows

Important links

Github Profile: http://github.com/vinitkumar

Linkedin Profile: http://in.linkedin.com/in/vinitatlinkedin/

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Administrator, In-Charge: Linux User Group, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011 - May 2012

Administrator: Web and DC server, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011- May 2012

BLog

Gotchacode Tech-blog covering topics related to web and Open Source. www.gotchacode.com